ALMAS BAIMAGAMBETOV

WORK EXPERIENCE

OCT. 2017 - PRESENT	PART-TIME LECTURER & MODULE LEADER IN GAME DEVELOPMENT UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON, UK
OCT. 2015 - PRESENT	EDUCATION SUPPORT SOFTWARE DEVELOPER UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON, UK
Ост. 2015 - Ост. 2017	Hourly-Paid Lecturer in Programming and Game Design & Development University of Brighton, UK
June 2014 - Oct. 2016	English-Russian Interpreter (Zero-Hour Contract) LLP AktubNIGRI, Kazakhstan
JAN 2013 - OCT. 2016	In-house Programmer (Zero-Hour Contract) LLP AktubNIGRI, Kazakhstan
OCT. 2012 - FEB. 2015	(VOLUNTEER) GUEST SPEAKER AND MENTOR FOR IT STUDENTS BELLERBYS COLLEGE, UK

EDUCATION

July 2015 - Present	PHD IN COMPUTING, ENGINEERING AND MATHEMATICS THESIS: AUTOMATED VISUALIZATION OF GROUPED NETWORKS KEYWORDS: SET THEORY, GRAPH THEORY, TOPOLOGY, COMPUTATIONAL GEOMETRY & GRAPHICS, EULER DIAGRAMS UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON, UK
Ост.2012 - July 2015	BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (GAMES), UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON, UK FIRST CLASS HONOURS FINAL YEAR PROJECT: ANALYSIS OF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ISSUES IN LARGE SCALE GAMES GRADE: 87% (A+) MODULES STUDIED
SEPT. 2011 - JUNE 2012	Foundation Degree in IT, Bellerbys College, UK Grade: 94% (A+)
JULY 2011	English Language Training, St. Giles International, UK Final Level: Advanced

SCHOLARSHIPS AND CERTIFICATES

SEPT. 2015	International Research Scholarship, University of Brighton
JULY 2015	BEST FINAL YEAR DEVELOPMENT PROJECT, UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON
Nov. 2014	ACADEMIC MERIT BASED SCHOLARSHIP, UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON
Nov. 2013	ACADEMIC MERIT BASED SCHOLARSHIP, UNIVERSITY OF BRIGHTON
June 2012	Top #1 Foundation Student, Bellerbys College
MAY 2012	BEST IT STUDENT, BELLERBYS COLLEGE

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: FLUENT / PROFESSIONAL

KAZAKH: NATIVE RUSSIAN: NATIVE

KEY PERSONAL SKILLS

• THEORETICAL AND ANALYTICAL PROBLEM-SOLVING SKILLS

- SELF-MOTIVATED, HARD-WORKING AND INDEPENDENT
- ABILITY TO QUICKLY ADAPT TO NEW TECHNOLOGIES AND LEARNING ENVIRONMENTS
- ABILITY TO QUICKLY ESTABLISH INTER-PERSONAL COMMUNICATION
- · ABILITY TO LEAD, MANAGE AND OVERSEE DIFFERENT ASPECTS OF VARIOUS DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

BEGINNER: UNITY, SQL, HTML, CSS, HASKELL, PYTHON, NODE.JS, SPRING INTERMEDIATE: C++, JS, SDL2, OPENGL, GIT, WIN/MAC/LINUX, AGILE, LETEX,

ALGORITHMS AND DATA STRUCTURES

ADVANCED: JAVA, JAVAFX, KOTLIN,

Game Engine Development (ECS, Al, UI, IO, Serialization, Physics, event systems, Networking, Scripting, etc.),

API DESIGN, TDD, FDD, DDD, CI,

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PRINCIPLES AND PRACTICES

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

EDUCATION, TECHNOLOGY, OPEN-SOURCE, SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT, COMPUTER SCIENCE DATA VISUALIZATION, AUTOMATED GRAPHICAL LAYOUT GENERATION CHESS

RESEARCH

FEB. 2018	VISUALIZATION OF GROUPED NETWORKS (ACCEPTED DIAGRAMS GRADUATE SYMPOSIUM 2018 CONF.)
FEB. 2018	GENERATING EFFECTIVE EULER DIAGRAMS (ACCEPTED LONG PAPER DIAGRAMS 2018 CONF.)
MAY 2017	Novel Algorithm for Euler Diagram Generation (UoB Conf.)
MARCH 2017	DATA VISUALIZATION WORKSHOP (PRESENTER AT DATA VIS BRIGHTON MEETUP)
FEB. 2017	An Inductive Approach to P-preserving Euler Diagram Generation (VMG Talk)
June 2016	GROUPED NETWORKS AND ASSOCIATED CHALLENGES (UOB CONF.)
MAY 2016	Euler Diagram Generation Techniques (VMG Talk)

BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (GAMES) GRADES

Module		CREDITS
MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT		20
PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES, CONCURRENCY AND CLIENT SERVER COMPUTING		20
Applied Intelligent Systems		10
EMERGING GAMES TECHNOLOGIES		20
Computer Graphics Algorithms		10
Final Year Project		40

STATEMENT

I AM AN ACTIVE RESEARCHER IN THE FIELD OF AUTOMATED DIAGRAM GENERATION. I TEACH A RANGE OF THEORETICAL AND PRACTICAL COMPUTER SCIENCE MODULES TO 1ST, 2ND AND 3RD YEAR UNIVERSITY STUDENTS. I AM THE AUTHOR AND MAINTAINER OF FXGL, A GAME ENGINE USED BY MULTIPLE ACADEMIC INSTITUTIONS TO TEACH GAME DEVELOPMENT. I RUN AN EDUCATIONAL YOUTUBE CHANNEL COVERING GAME AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT.

CONTACT DETAILS AND PORTFOLIO

GITHUB | LINKEDIN | A.BAIMAGAMBETOV@BRIGHTON.AC.UK